A Guide to the Moore Family Papers, 1789-1864
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Moore Family Papers, 1789-1864
The Library of Virginia
21734
10 leaves and 38 pages
Moore Family
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Louis H. Stoneman of Columbia, Virginia, 2 July 1940.
Biographical Information
Riley Moore settled at Mt. Jackson in what would become Shenandoah County, Virginia, in 1734. His grandson, Aaron Moore (1770-1843) and Aaron's son Charles Moore (1809-1870) became prosperous land owners and prominent citizens of Shenandoah County.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1789-1864, of the Moore family of Shenandoah County, Virginia, consisting of deeds and land grants for property in Shenandoah County, and in the Illinois territory and in Indiana; correspondence concerning property in Indiana and other matters; receipts, 1812 and 1864, to members of the Moore family; will, 24 June 1835, of Sarah Hawkins (d. 1835) of Shenandoah County; power of attorney, 13 February 1844; certificate, 23 July 1862, issued by the Confederate government to John C. Suiton; voucher, 10 September 1864; bill of complaint, no date, by Anne Harrod (d. 1843) of Mercer County, Kentucky, against Aaron Mercer of Shenandoah County; and notes, no date, concerning property purchased from Phillip Delander.
Contents List
- Deed, 8 April 1789, for 500 acres in the Illinois territory from George Rogers Clark (1752-1818), William Clark (1770-1838), Alexander Breckenridge (d. 1801), William Croghan (1744-1822), John Baleys, James Francis Moore, and Andrew Heth, Commissioners for apportioning the lands granted the Illinois Regiment to William Harrod.
- Deed, 7 July 1789, for 100 acres in the Illinois territory, from Clark, Clark, Breckinridge, Moore, Croghan, Robert Breckinridge (d. 1833), and Richard Taylor, Commissioners, to Christopher Greenup (ca. 1750-1818), assignee of Francis McDermid.
- Deed, 7 July 1789, for 100 acres in the Illinois territory from Clark, Clark, Breckinridge, Breckinridge, Taylor, Croghan, and Richard Terrell, Commissioners, to Greenup, assignee of John Hunter, assignee of Dominic Flanagan.
- Deed, 29 October 1802, for two tracts of land in the "Illinios grant" from Greenup of Franklin County, Kentucky, to Aaron Moore (1770-1843) of Shenandoah County, Virginia.
- Deed, dated and recorded 10 June 1805, for 30 acres in Shenandoah County from John and Elizabeth Pennywit to Michael Sigler (1753-1833), all of Shenandoah County.
- Receipt, 13 April 1812, from Lewis Moore to Aaron Moore.
- Deed, dated 27 May 1814 and recorded 13 March 1815, for 227 acres from William and Mary Moore to Aaron Moore, all of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 15 February 1815 and recorded 22 April 1815, for 500 acres in the Indiana territory from Charles and Heningham Copland of Richmond, Virginia to Aaron Moore.
- Deed, 25 November 1819, for 100 acres in Indiana from Breckinridge, Croghan, and Taylor, Commissioners, to Aaron Moore, assignee of Jacob Miller (1798-1875).
- Will, 24 June 1835, of Sarah Hawkins (d. 1835) of Shenandoah County.
- Land grant, 30 June 1837, for 559 39/100 acres in Indiana from President Martin Van Buren (1782-1862) to Samuel Moore (1807-1870) of Shenandoah County.
- Power of attorney, 13 February 1844, from Original and Dorcas Young to Reuben Young, all of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 11 August 1853 and recorded 12 May 1855, for certain land in Shenandoah County from John H. Knock of Washington D.C. to William and Anthony Miller of Shenandoah County.
- Deed, dated 29 September 1853 and recorded 12 May 1855, for certain land in Shenandoah County from John and Magdaline Walker to Anthony Miller.
- Letter, 7 September 1857, concerning a deed for property from J. B. Dodge of Koscusk County, Indiana, to Charles Moore (1809-1871) of Shenandoah County.
- Certificate 541, 23 July 1862, for $2500 issued by the Confederate States of America to John C. Suiton.
- Receipt, January 1864, to Charles Moore.
- Voucher, 10 September 1864, from Captain Robert T. Crouch (d. 1897), C.S.A., to Charles Moore.
- Deed, dated 8 November 1864 and recorded 18 November 1864, for certain land in Indiana from John W. R. Moore to Joseph Orr, both of La Porte County, Indiana.
- Letter, 14 December 1864, from Isaac White of Staunton, Virginia, to Charles Moore.
- Bill of complaint, no date, by Anne Harrod (d. 1843) of Mercer County, Kentucky, against Aaron Moore of Shenandoah County.
- Notes, no date, concerning land bought from Phillip Delander.